honeybadger.io 2019-03-13

# Privacy Statement - Honeybadger

_Last Updated February 7th, 2018_

Protecting your private information is our priority. This Privacy Statement applies to the www.honeybadger.io website operated by Honeybadger Industries LLC and other sites, apps, or services that link to this Statement, and it governs collection, usage, and disclosure of your personal information. This Statement does not apply to websites, applications, or services that link to different privacy statements.

We collect and process personal information about you with your consent and/or as necessary to provide the products you use, operate our business, meet our contractual and legal obligations, protect the security of our systems and our customers, or fulfill other legitimate interests.

## Collection of Your Personal Information

Honeybadger may collect personal information in a variety of ways when you use our services. We collect personal information you provide to us, such as your name and email address. If you purchase Honeybadger's products and services, we collect billing and credit card information. We may gather additional personal or non-personal information in the future. Some services may not be available or function correctly if you are not willing to provide personal information. We may also obtain information from other sources and combine that with information we collect on our services.

Information about your computer hardware and software may be automatically collected by Honeybadger when you visit our sites. This information can include: your IP address, operating system, browser type, domain names, access times, language, and referring website addresses. When you use our mobile application we may collect certain information about your device automatically, including device identifier and operating system.

**Cookies.** We may automatically collect information using "cookies". Cookies are small data files stored on your hard drive by a website. Among other things, cookies help us improve our services and your experience. We use cookies to see which areas and features are popular and to count visits to our services.

**Web Beacons.** We may collect information using web beacons. Web beacons are electronic images that may be used on our services or in our emails. We use web beacons to deliver cookies, count visits, understand usage and campaign effectiveness and to tell if an email has been opened and acted upon.

**Analytics.** Third parties who provide us with analytics services for the services may also automatically collect some of the information described above, including, for example, IP address, access times, browser type and language, device type, device identifiers and Wi-Fi information. Please consult the respective privacy policies and statements of these third parties for more information, including how [Google Analytics](https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/), [Mixpanel](https://mixpanel.com/privacy/), [Segment](https://segment.com/docs/legal/privacy/), [Amplitude](https://amplitude.com/privacy), [Intercom](https://www.intercom.com/terms-and-policies#privacy), and [Crashlytics](http://try.crashlytics.com/terms/privacy-policy.pdf) use this data.

Please keep in mind that if you directly disclose personal information or sensitive data through Honeybadger's public message boards, this information may be collected and used by others. We encourage you to be careful with how you use these services.

**Use of Your Personal Information**

Honeybadger collects and uses your personal information as described in this Statement or disclosed to you in our services, to operate its website(s), and deliver the services you have requested. For example, we may use your information to:

  * operate and improve our internal operations, systems, products, and services;
  * understand you and your preferences to enhance your experience and enjoyment using our services;
  * respond to your comments and questions and provide customer service;
  * send you related information, including confirmations, invoices, technical notices, updates, security alerts, and support and administrative messages;
  * link or combine information about you with other personal information we get from third parties, to help understand your needs and provide you with better and more personalized service; and
  * protect, investigate, and deter against fraudulent, unauthorized, or illegal activity.

Honeybadger may also use your personally identifiable information to inform you of other products or services available from Honeybadger and its affiliates and partners. Honeybadger may also contact you via surveys to conduct research about your opinion of current services or of potential new services that may be offered.

## Disclosure of Your Personal Information

Honeybadger does not sell, rent or lease its customer lists to third parties. We may share your information with your consent. Honeybadger may share data with trusted partners and service providers to help provide backup and disaster-recovery services, provide data storage and processing services, perform statistical analysis, send you email or postal mail, provide customer support, or arrange for deliveries. All such third parties are prohibited from using your personal information except to provide these services to Honeybadger, and they are required to maintain the confidentiality of your information.

Honeybadger may include personal data in connection with or during negotiation of any merger, financing, acquisitions, bankruptcy, dissolution, transaction or proceeding involving sale, transfer, divestiture, or disclosure of all or a portion of our business or assets to another company.

Honeybadger may disclose your personal information to respond to lawful requests or in the good faith belief that such action is necessary to: (a) conform to the edicts of the law or comply with legal process served on Honeybadger or the site; (b) protect and defend the rights or property of Honeybadger, its customers, and others; (c) respond to valid requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements; (d) protect against legal liability; and, (e) act under emergency to protect the personal safety of users of Honeybadger, its customers, or the public.

We may also share aggregated or deidentified information.

## Your Information Choices and Changes

If you wish to ask for access, correction, or deletion of any of your personal information held by us or a change in the way we use your information (for which we reserve the right to charge you a fee, as permitted by applicable law), please contact us at: [support@honeybadger.io](mailto:support@honeybadger.io). However, we may decline requests that are unreasonable, prohibited by law, or are not required to be honored by applicable law.

You may opt out of receiving promotional emails from us by following the instructions in those emails. If you opt out, we may still send you non-promotional emails, such as emails about your accounts or our ongoing business relations. You may also send requests about your contact preferences, changes to your information including requests to opt-out of sharing your personal information with third parties by emailing [support@honeybadger.io](mailto:support@honeybadger.io).

You have the ability to accept or decline cookies. Most Web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. If you choose to decline cookies, you may not be able to fully experience the interactive features of the Honeybadger services or websites you visit.

Our third-party analytics and advertising partners may provide you with options to opt-out of certain information collection. For more information about the applicable choices they provide you, please visit: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>, <https://mixpanel.com/privacy/>, <https://segment.com/docs/legal/privacy/>, <https://amplitude.com/privacy>, <https://www.intercom.com/terms-and-policies#privacy>, and <http://try.crashlytics.com/terms/privacy-policy.pdf>.

There are many ways through which web browser signals and other similar mechanisms (for example, "Do Not Track") can indicate your choice to disable tracking, and, while we and others give you choices described in this Statement, we do not currently honor these mechanisms.

## Security of your Personal Information

Honeybadger takes reasonable steps to help secure your personal information in an effort to prevent loss, misuse, and unauthorized access, use, alteration, destruction, or disclosure.

## Transfers of Your Personal Information

Personal information we collect may be stored and processed in your region, in the United States or in any other country where we or our affiliates, subsidiaries or service providers maintain facilities. We maintain primary data centers in the United States. We take steps designed to ensure that the data we collect under this Statement is processed according to the provisions of this Statement and applicable law wherever the data is located.

When we transfer personal information from the European Economic Area and Switzerland to other countries, some of which have not been determined by the European Commission to have an adequate level of data protection, we use a variety of legal mechanisms, including contracts, in an effort to help ensure your rights and protections.

## For EU Users - Your European Privacy Rights

We adhere to applicable data protection laws in the European Economic Area, which, if applicable to you, includes the following rights:

  * If we are processing personal information based on your consent, you have a right to withdraw consent at any time for future processing;
  * You have a right to request access to, rectification, or erasure of your personal information, or to transfer or receive a copy of your personal information in a usable format;
  * You have a right to object to the processing of your personal information under certain circumstances; and
  * You have a right to lodge a complaint with a data protection authority.

## For EU Users - Privacy Shield

Honeybadger complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States, respectively. Honeybadger has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles of Notice, Choice, Accountability for Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation, Access, and Recourse, Enforcement and Liability. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. The Federal Trade Commission (FTC) has jurisdiction over Honeybadger's compliance with the Privacy Shield. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit [https://www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/).

Our participation in Privacy Shield applies to personal data that is received from the European Economic Area and Switzerland. We will comply with the Privacy Shield Principles in respect of all such personal data.

In compliance with the EU-U.S. and Swiss Privacy Shield Principles, Honeybadger commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first [contact us](mailto:support@honeybadger.io). Honeybadger has further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the EU-U.S. and Swiss Privacy Shield Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism free of charge to you through [JAMS](https://www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield). Finally, you may have the right to invoke binding arbitration to resolve complaints, as described in [Annex I](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=ANNEX-I-introduction) to the Privacy Shield Principles.

If we transfer your personal information to a third party agent or service provider for processing, we remain potentially liable under the Privacy Shield Principles if our third party agent or service provider processes your personal information in a manner inconsistent with the Privacy Shield Principles and this causes you harm, unless we are able to show that we are not responsible for the event leading to that harm.

## Storage and Retention of Your Personal Information

We retain your personal information for as long as necessary to provide services requested by you, or for other essential purposes such as complying with our legal obligations, resolving disputes, and enforcing our agreements. Because these needs can vary for different data types in the context of different services, actual retention periods can vary significantly. The criteria used to determine retention include:

  1. _How long is the personal information needed to provide applicable services?_ This includes such things as maintaining and improving the performance of the services, enabling system security measures, and maintaining appropriate business and financial records.
  2. _Do users provide, create, or maintain the data with the expectation we will retain it until they affirmatively remove it?_ In such cases, we may maintain the data until actively deleted by the user.
  3. _Is the personal information of a sensitive type?_ If so, a shortened retention time may be appropriate.
  4. _Are we subject to a legal, contractual, or similar obligation to retain the data?_ Examples can include mandatory data retention laws in the applicable jurisdiction, government orders to preserve data, or data that must be retained for the purposes of litigation.

## Changes to This Statement

Honeybadger will occasionally update this Privacy Statement from time to time. If we make any changes to this Statement, we will change the "Last Updated" date above or by providing such notice about or obtaining consent to changes as may be required by applicable law. Honeybadger encourages you to periodically review this Statement to be informed of how Honeybadger is protecting your information.

## Questions

If you have any questions about this policy, or if you wish to lodge a complaint about our privacy practices, please contact us at [support@honeybadger.io](mailto:support@honeybadger.io).
